ABHINAV SARNA

M: +91 98119 47504 | Jaipur, IN

E: sarna.abhinav@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhinav-sarna-9a801b54

PROFILE

Performance-driven and dedicated Business Analyst/Data Enthusiast with a strong attention to detail and accuracy. Exceptional record of delivering cost effective, high performance technology solutions to challenging business demands. Extensive experience in producing reports, improving data collection, data entry and analysis processes. Multi-skilled and diligent worker with strong organizational and problem-solving skills. Proven communication skills with the ability to remain calm in stressful situations.

SKILLS AND TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

- Data Management
- Data Mining
- · Data Analysis
- Machine Learning
- Quality Assurance
- Project Management

- Business Analysis
- Business Development
- Strategic Planning
- Due Diligence
- Reporting
- Microsoft Office

- MySQL
- Python
- Tableau
- Jira
- Microsoft CRM
- Power BI

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Specialist April 2019 – Aug 2020

Yodify Inc., Calgary

- Collected and entered data from various resources, organize it and create database for Yodify and maintained data quality
- Collaborated with stakeholders (internally and externally) across functions to develop policies and procedures which enforce repeatable and reliable processes, reducing variability, increasing efficiency and enhancing overall data quality and compliance
- · Managed product demonstration via onsite visits, teleconferences, technical meet-ups and webinars
- Mapped and analyzed exact customer requirements for custom design solutions & trouble shooting complex problems
- Provided effective resolution of customer quires related to product & hence improved customer relationships
- Identified shortcoming in the clarity and fluidity of user experience in the Yodify's e-commerce website while creating and implementing improvement strategies
- Performed market research for better digital marketing & sales solicitations in North America
- Assisted with management of the data team by training and mentoring new hires, performing QA & QC, identifying and delegating weekly tasks to the team members on Jira
- Completed special projects and/or market research as requested

Data Analyst

February 2019 – March 2019

Bayer Crop Science Inc., Calgary

- Supported Bayer's acquisition data merger thru Microsoft BI analysis and cloud CRM Dynamics
- Integrated Customer Relationship Management (CRM) to Master Data Management (MDM) database through Data Reconciliation

Petroleum Engineer

October 2013 - April 2016

VACA Energy LLC, Beverly Hills

Vaca Energy LLC, is an oil and gas portfolio company of the private equity fund Clarity Partners L.P. Worked on ultra heavy (7^oAPI) and deep oil fields (Oxnard & West Montalvo) in California.

- Analyzed, maintained and history matched the development and production history of wells for reserve assessment and future optimization. Saved the company up to \$2 million on various projects
- Monitored and analyzed production data to make recommendations for improvement of daily oil & gas production, risk identification and made long term production forecasts

- Created and maintained details track sheets, job requirement lists, anticipated issues, job status and final reports of all field jobs and engineering studies
- Designed work plans for consultants and vendors which defined scope, processes to be used, alternatives, risks etc and supervised/participated in their implementation on field
- Evaluated potential investment/acquisition prospects by performing engineering and technical due diligence
- Communicated the reasoning and the pros & cons of field jobs performed in easy to understand models and charts to company's management and non-technical personal
- Represented Vaca Energy LLC. at various government meetings & technical seminars on upcoming technology market

Junior Petroleum Engineer

September 2008 - September 2009

SMP Petro Minerals Enterprises Pvt. Ltd., India

SMP Petro Minerals is an oil and gas consultancy firm providing technical expertise to the project owned by Global Steel Holding Limited located in Republic of Georgia. Worked on Supsa – Shromisubani oil fields.

- Collaborated with field experts to perform engineering & simulation studies
- Facilitated field jobs such as installation of various artificial lifts, re-perforations and well stimulation
- Coordinated daily team meetings and maintained MOM logs to provide weekly/monthly status to management and regulatory agencies
- Performed economic analysis, reserve determination etc. for annual production budgets and forecast
- Prepared notices and applications for compliance for Regulatory Agencies
- Managed presale, sales of oil & procurement procedure and documents

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Administrative Data Analyst

July 2016 - December 2017

Worked for the Facilities Manager, USC Libraries, Los Angeles.

- Performed data analysis on various library project databases to assist with feasibility studies and strategic planning
- Generated worksheets for data entry and record keeping; assisted with tracking work orders and provided status updates
- Assisted with the implementation of security protocols and procedures
- Audited the existing records and datasets and made updates as necessary

Volunteer Experience as Secretary & Treasurer

October 2009 - October 2010

Dr. Navtej Sarna Memorial Charitable Trust, India

Worked as Secretary and Treasurer of the Trust

- Planned and supervised various activities of the Trust such as Medical Camps, Handicraft Camps, Education Counseling Camps etc
- Reviewed & evaluated various donation proposals and visited sited to better understand the scope of work to be performed with the donation
- Organized fund raisers for the Trust
- Budgeted the accounts of the Trust

EDUCATION

Certificate in Smart Oil Field Technologies

January 2016 - August 2018

University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA

January 2011 - August 2013

Master of Science in Petroleum Engineering
University of Southern California. Los Angeles. CA

August 2004 - May 2008

Bachelor of Engineering in Petroleum Engineering

University of Petroleum & Energy Studies, India

CERTIFICATIONS

SQL - MySQL for Data Analytics and Business Intelligence; Udemy

April 2020

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Punjabi, German and French (German & French at High School Level)